A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Attorney General Opinions, 1781-1875
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Attorney General Opinions, 1781-1875
The Library of Virginia
APA 87
.70 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
From 1776 to 1851, the Attorney General was elected by the General Assembly, or, in case of vacancy, appointed by the governor for an undefined term. The Virginia Constitution of 1851 introduced popular election and four-year terms. After the 1851 constitution, vacancies would be filled by the General Assembly, if they were in session, or by the governor. Edmund Randolph served as the first Attorney General of Virginia after Independence.
Scope and Content
Opinions, 1781-1875, of the Attorney General for the Auditor of Public Accounts. The opinions are often written into letters or on notes. Virginia Attorney Generals include Edmund Randolph (1776-1786), James Innes (1786-1796), Robert Brooke (1796-1800), Philip Norborne Nicholas (1800-1819), John Robertson (1819-1834), Sidney Smith Baxter (1834-1852), Willis Perry Bocock (1852-1857), John Randolph Tucker (1857-1865), James Craig Taylor (1870-1874), and Raleigh Travers Daniel (1874-1877). Topics include: pay for militia and military; salary of Penitentiary keeper; sale of delinquent lands; appropriations for Virginia Military Institute; court costs; right to tax persons employed and residing in Harpers Ferry; railroad taxes; acts regulating Life Insurance Companies; payment for slaves condemned to sale and transportation; tax exemptions of theatrical performances; taxation for the manufacturers of ale or beer; if merchants can sell apple or peach barndy without an additional license; taxing circus performers; interest on bank dividends; taxes on emancipated slaves; sale of liquor by physicians and apothecaries; taxation of penitentiary convicts; taxation of officers and employees of the Navy; taxation of Confederate officers; and funding of Treasury notes, among other topics.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Opinions (Edmund Randolph), 1781 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Opinions (Edmund Randolph), 1782 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Opinions (Edmund Randolph), 1783 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Opinions (Edmund Randolph), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Opinions (Edmund Randolph), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Opinions (Edmund Randolph), 1786 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Opinions (James Innes), 1787 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Opinions (James Innes), 1788 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Opinions (James Innes), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Opinions (Robert Brooke), 1799 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Opinions (Philip Norborne Nicholas), 1815 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Opinions (Philip Norborne Nicholas), 1816 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Opinions (Philip Norborne Nicholas), 1818 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Opinions (John Robertson), 1819 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Opinions (John Robertson), 1820 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Opinions (John Robertson), 1821 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Opinions (John Robertson), 1826 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Opinions (John Robertson), 1832 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1842 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1843 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1844 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1846 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1847 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1848 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1849 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1850 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Opinions (Sidney Smith Baxter), 1851 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Opinions (Willis Perry Bocock), 1852 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Opinions (Willis Perry Bocock), 1855 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Opinions (Willis Perry Bocock), 1856 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Opinions (Willis Perry Bocock and John Randolph Tucker), 1857 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1858 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1859 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1860 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1861 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1862 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1863 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1864 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Opinions (John Randolph Tucker), 1865 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Opinions (James Craig Taylor), 1873 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Opinions (Raleigh Travers Daniel), 1874 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Opinions (Raleigh Travers Daniel), 1875 (Box 2, Folder 8)